Renee Ying Hui SEET Mobile: +65 96450705

Email: renee.seet@u.nus.edu
Skype: iamreneeseet@hotmail.com
GitHub: github.com/ReneeSeet
Website: reneeseet.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/renee-seet-577573162



Personal Statement

About Me

I am a Year 3 Computer Science undergraduate at the National University of Singapore. Growing up in a family that runs an IT company, I have been consistently exposed to upcoming technology and innovative business concepts from a young age. I am amazed by how these two entities are intertwined and how they complement each other. In less than a decade, we have seen how IT businesses revolutionize the world. Whatsapp has become our main form of communication daily, and people now meet their potential life partners on social media platforms like Facebook and Tinder. IT businesses have become an integral part of everyday life. Having benefitted from such revolutionary IT businesses, I aspire to create my own tech start-up and thus chose computing as my major - hoping to someday influence a change like that.

My very first IT project during my freshman summer break, Orbital, was the closest experience I have to starting my own business, I enjoyed nurturing the project from ground zero to a fully usable application. My project, Clockwork, was a scheduler that helped linked businesses to customers who wanted to schedule appointments on their own. What thrilled me even more was how my application potentially improved people's lives and businesses' productivity.

During my other internship opportunities at Rovo and Chirpey, two tech start-ups in Singapore, I assisted to create applications and scrapers that these companies are now using. While these were new languages and frameworks, I was open to learning. I gained immensely from my time with these companies. It also gives me a great sense of satisfaction knowing that my contributions have been put to use in reality.

I personally feel that Computing is not about having overreaching knowledge but is about learning how to learn. Building upon the foundation that I have from University, I have learnt new algorithms and languages to create my own programs and solutions. In the near future, I would like to focus on software engineering and am also open to both front-end and back-end development.

Also, I am an optimistic and bubbly individual. I enjoy meeting people and learning about them. As an aspiring software engineer, I know that it is crucial to expand my social circle and understand others better. I want to hear the new problems that people face daily and create new solutions for them with the tech knowledge I have. I believe strongly that in today's world, technology can be a helpful problem-solving tool. For example, being animal lovers, my brother and I realized that missing pets were common in Singapore and thus created a platform, PetsRecall, for people to reunite with their lost pets. I would like to continue using my tech knowledge to help solve bigger social issues.

Internship Objectives

I believe that interning works both ways.

Besides gaining technical knowledge during this internship, I would also like to experience first-hand how tech startups build their businesses – from the idealization, team-building, marketing, financing to the problem-solving. This will be invaluable knowledge and experience for me in my own future IT business.

Besides learning and gaining experience on my end, my other key priority is to contribute to your company. I will use what I know and have learnt to help build your company. I am a hard worker and am always up for a new challenge and believe my adaptability and willingness to learn will benefit your company greatly.

Education

Aug 2016 - Present

National University of Singapore
Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science
Planned Focus Area: Software Engineering
(Course details in Appendix A)

Temasek Junior College
Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced
Level

Singapore

Work Experience

Aug 2018 - Present SRECTrade Inc USA

SRECTrade, Inc. focuses Solar Renewable Energy Certificate (SREC) markets by Transacting SRECs, developing useful software for market participants and providing detailed research and analysis on market trends.

Web development Intern

- Helping to solve bugs and developing features for SRECTrade website.
- Learn about the SREC market

Feb 2018 – Jul 2018 Chirpey Singapore

A fresh Start-up by NUS students which aims to create a mobile application that empowers female travelers

Part time front-end developer

Worked with React Native while developing Application UI

Dec 2017 – Mid Jan Rovo Singapore
2018 Start-up that created a mobile application that helps users find sports

Start-up that created a mobile application that helps users find sports buddies

Software Engineering Intern

- · Coded Scrappers using JavaScript to get sports facilities' data
- Stored sports facilities' data in PostgreSQL
- Developed Rovo's Sports facilities page using React framework

Dec 2015 – August 2016 ASC Singapore

Small Medium Enterprise (SME) that provides IT Solutions and Cards System

Part time

- Involved in the development of website, www.cardiflex.sg
- Assisted in the development of business solution software e.g. Cardiflex™ E-Print Requisition System & Cardiflex™ Self-Operating Card System
- · Onsite training of customers

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Aug 2018 – Present NUS Overseas College Silicon Valley Batch 34

A year-long program that allows students to intern with tech startups located in Silicon Valley as well as take entrepreneurship-related and discipline-based courses at Stanford University.

May 2017 – July 2017 NUS Orbital

Built and design an Android-based scheduler paired application, Customer-end *ClockWork* and Business-end *ClockWork Business*,

that aims to enhance business processes and encourage customer interaction. Developed on *Android Studios* and data are stored on

Firebase.

Orbital is a self-directed, independent project organized by NUS School of Computing which allows Year 1 students to pick up software

development skills on their own using sources on the web.

June 2017 **2017 Cyber Defenders Discovery Camp**

7 Cyber Defenders Discovery Camp Singapore

Singapore

Achieve Bronze

Organized by Defence Science and Technology Agency Singapore. The competition consists of participants from local universities and

colleges and involved managing and protecting of server.

August 2017 – Jan 2018 School Contribution

School Contribution Singapore
Tech Director for NUS BiZiT Society

BiZiT is a student-run organization that aims to be the nurturing ground for talents interested in building up their knowledge in IT and Business

domains.

Jan 2016 - Present PetsRecall.com Singapore

Assisted in the development of website and promotion via social media

platforms.

С

PetsRecall is an initiative aimed to reunite Singaporean pet owners

with their lost pets.

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming Java Proficient

Proficient

Web HTML, CSS Proficient

JavaScript, Node.js Intermediate
React Intermediate
PHP Intermediate

Mobile Android Studios Intermediate

React Native Basic

DatabasePostgreSQL DBMSIntermediate

Firebase Intermediate SQL Intermediate

Markup XML Basic

Version Control Tools Git Proficient

Language Proficiency

Spoken English – fluent; Mandarin – fluent

Written English – competent; Chinese – competent

Other Activities

Jan 2018	2018 Hack n Roll Participated in Singapore largest student overnight hackathon organized by NUS Hackers. In a group of 4, we developed a quirky Telegram bot @MyDreamBoyFriendBot that aims to be the perfect boyfriend. The bot was developed using Java and was hosted on DigitalOcean.
Aug 2017	Orientation Group Leader for 2017 NUS School of Computing (SoC) Freshmen Orientation Camp Led a group of 14 freshmen through camp and ensuring that they were well integrated and prepared for university
Aug 2016	2016 NUS Inter-Faculty Games SoC Women's Volleyball Captain Represented School of Computing to compete with other faculties. Also planned and led trainings for teammates

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 4.00 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug – Nov 2016	Year 1/Semester 1	Programming Methodology	В
		Discrete Structures	S
		Linear Algebra I	B+
		Calculus for Computing	S
		Understanding the Changing Global Economic Landscape	B+
Jan – May 2017	Year 1/Semester 2	Data Structures and Algorithms I	S
		Computer Organization	В
		Quantitative Reasoning	S
		Everyday Life of Chinese Singaporean: Past & present	S
		General Biology	B+
Aug – Nov 2017	Year 2/Semester 1	Data Structures and Algorithms II	B+
		Software Engineering #	Α
		Effective Communication for Computing	A-
		Introduction to Operating Systems	В
		Asking Questions	S
Jan – May 2018	Year 2/Semester 2	Database Systems	In-progress
		Introduction to Computer Networks	In-progress
		IS Innovation in Organisations and Society	In-progress
		Probability and Statistics	In-progress
		Traditional Chinese Knowledge of Health and Well-Being	In-progress

Software Engineering introduces necessary conceptual and analytical tools for systematic and rigorous development of software systems. It covers four main areas of software development, namely object-oriented system analysis, object-oriented system modelling and design, implementation, and testing. Emphasising on system modelling, design and implementation of software modules that work cooperatively to fulfill the system's requirements. Tools for software development, such as Unified Modelling Language, program specification, and testing methods as wells as software engineering issues such as modularisation criteria, program correctness, and software quality were taught.

This module includes a semester long project done in a team of 4 people. We were given a pre-coded address book and were tasked to improve it. My team and I modified the address book to a software, CYNC, that aims to help businesses manage customers. CYNC was written in Java and Javafx using Intellij. This module was paired with **Effective Communication for Computing** where I learnt how to document, package and present a software.

NUS Grading Scale:

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn